<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model
  href="https://vault.tei-c.org/P5/current/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng"
  schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"
  type="application/xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Bohemian Rapsody: lyrics digital edition</title>
                <author>Queen</author>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>compiled by</resp>
                    <name>Valentino Castagna</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition n = "1">Teddaccio editions<date>, November 2023</date></edition>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Annoteted by</resp>
                    <name>Valentino Castagna</name>
                </respStmt>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Me, myself and I</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Bologna</pubPlace>
                <availability><p>Open Access</p></availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>    
                <bibl>
                    <title level = "a">Bohemian Rapsody</title>
                    <author>Queen</author>.
                    From <title level="m">"A Night at the Opera"</title>
                    <date>(1975)</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>    
    </teiHeader>
    <text> 
        <body>
                   
                <lg>
                    <head>[Intro]</head>
                    <l>Is this the real life? Is this just fantasy?</l>
                    <l>Caught in a landslide, no escape from reality</l>
                    <l>Open your eyes, look up to the skies and see</l>
                    <l>I'm just a poor boy, I need no sympathy</l>
                    <l>Because I'm easy come, easy go, little high, little low</l>
                    <l>Any way the wind blows doesn't really matter to me, to me</l>
                </lg>

                <lg>
                    <head>[Ballad Verse]</head>
                    <l>Mama, just killed a man</l>
                    <l>Put a gun against his head, pulled my trigger, now he's dead</l>
                    <l>Mama, life had just begun</l>
                    <l>But now I've gone and thrown it all away</l>
                    <l>Mama, ooh, didn't mean to make you cry</l>
                    <l>If I'm not back again this time tomorrow</l>
                    <l>Carry on, carry on as if nothing really matters</l>
                </lg>

                <lg>
                    <head>[Ballad Verse 2]</head>
                    <l>Too late, my time has come</l>
                    <l>Sends shivers down my spine, body's aching all the time</l>
                    <l>Goodbye, everybody, I've got to go</l>
                    <l>Gotta leave you all behind and face the truth</l>
                    <l>Mama, ooh (Any way the wind blows)</l>
                    <l>I don't wanna die</l>
                    <l>I sometimes wish I'd never been born at all</l>
                </lg>
            
            
            <note>[Interlude: Guitar solo]</note>
                
                <lg>
                    <head>
                        <title>[Opera Section]</title>
                        <note>(lyrics in parenthesis are sung by a choir)</note>
                    </head>
                    <l>I see a little silhouetto of a man</l>
                    <l>Scaramouche, Scaramouche, will you do the Fandango?</l>
                    <l>Thunderbolt and lightning, very, very frightening me</l>
                    <l>(Galileo) Galileo, (Galileo) Galileo, Galileo Figaro magnifico</l>
                    <l>But I'm just a poor boy, nobody loves me</l>
                    <l>He's just a poor boy from a poor family</l>
                    <l>Spare him his life from this monstrosity</l>
                    <l>Easy come, easy go, will you let me go?</l>
                    <l>Bismillah! No, we will not let you go</l>
                    <l>(Let him go) Bismillah! We will not let you go</l>
                    <l>(Let him go) Bismillah! We will not let you go</l>
                    <l>(Let me go) Will not let you go</l>
                    <l>(Let me go) Will not let you go</l>
                    <l>(Never, never, never, never let me go) Ah</l>
                    <l>No, no, no, no, no, no, no</l>
                    <l>(Oh, mamma mia, mamma mia) Mamma mia, let me go</l>
                    <l>Beelzebub has a devil put aside for me, for me, for me!</l>
                </lg>
                
                <lg>
                    <head>[Bridge]</head>
                    <l>So you think you can stone me and spit in my eye?</l>
                    <l>So you think you can love me and leave me to die?</l>
                    <l>Oh, baby, can't do this to me, baby!</l>
                    <l>Just gotta get out, just gotta get right outta here</l>
                </lg>
                
                <lg>
                    <head>[Coda]</head>
                    <l>(Ooh, yeah, ooh, yeah)</l>
                    <l>Nothing really matters, anyone can see</l>
                    <l>Nothing really matters</l>
                    <l>Nothing really matters to me</l>
                    <l>Any way the wind blows</l>
                </lg>
        </body>
            
    </text>
</TEI>